{
    "id": "1c72d2705e2540fcac4509449162ea90",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I know a man ………………….. son studies in the US.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun whose can connect two clauses and replace possessive pronouns like his, her or their.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whose",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "89c394bdddc84f6fa9b634025572c89e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The thief ………………… stole the watch was punished.",
            "description": "Which can only be used to refer to things. Whom is an object pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "what",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "68aa3da3d03a48ecbf9e70f852f8aa2d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Show me the road ………………. leads to Agra.",
            "description": "Both that and which can refer to things. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "75be1493ab9d4f05bcd54642285668a6"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………….. does his best should be rewarded.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get the following: He does his best. He should be rewarded. The relative pronoun 'who' can connect two clauses and replace pronouns like he, she and they. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c79a77a9b9594532afc690f3513d6808"
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandfather ………………. I loved is dead.",
            "description": "Whom is the correct option here. Who is also possible in an informal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which",
                "Either who or whom"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "ef39db38283144ada959bd6f0fda3a41"
        },
        {
            "question": "Wellington ………………. defeated Napoleon at the Battle of Waterloo was a great general.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "29f783fcd514432f856f8c7ef567c56d"
        },
        {
            "question": "We met a child ……………. had lost his way.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "574b04a6da294487b3194c9fb478df6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is a rascal ……………… no one likes.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get the following: He is a rascal. No one likes him. \r\nThe relative pronoun ‘whom’ replaces words like him, her and them.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "which",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "63b9d76d23d74cf79a4784e6ae7faa0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "That boy ……………… you see over there plays very well.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get: That boy plays very well. You see him over there.\r\nThe relative pronoun ‘whom’ replaces words like him, her and them. 'Who' is also possible here in an informal style. \r\n",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b21d931357864f5fa68864bc5cbb0c3a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Here are the keys ………………. you were looking for.",
            "description": "Both 'that' and 'which' can refer to things. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9580f96a09cc48cdb1fbb82da482ac15"
        },
        {
            "question": "The dog bit the burglar ……………….. had broken into the house.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get the following: The dog bit the burglar. He had broken into the house. The relative pronoun who replaces words like he, she and they. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3aa1328ff9b243eeba75c835f585ed99"
        },
        {
            "question": "Coal ……………… is a useful mineral is found in many parts of the world.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get the following: Coal is a useful mineral. It is found in many parts of the world.\r\nThe relative pronoun ‘which’ replaces pronouns like it. \r\n",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "what",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6dd4948906944b7ebb12cca891ad0d96"
        }
    ]
}